So far in this lesson we've talked about why we hold meetings.
到目前为止，在本课中，我们已经讨论了为什么要举行会议。
We've talked about basically giving a proposal and how it's different from just throwing in an idea
我们已经讨论过基本上提出一个建议以及它与仅仅提出一个想法有何不同
and then how to respond to proposals or ideas from other people in a meeting.
然后如何回应会议中其他人的建议或想法。
Now what if we're actually the moderator of the meeting.
现在，如果我们实际上是会议的主持人怎么办。
This means the person who's in charge of the meeting doesn't necessarily mean the boss but someone who's
这意味着负责会议的人不一定是老板，而是负责会议的人。
responsible for keeping the meeting going.
负责保持会议的进行。
Well the primary responsibility the main job of this person is to make sure that things don't get out
那么这个人的主要职责就是确保事情不会泄露出去
of control out of hand or off track.
失控或偏离轨道。
We often use the phrase off track to say that things are going in the wrong direction.
我们经常使用偏离轨道这个短语来表示事情正朝着错误的方向发展。
We're supposed to be focused on topic A but now we're talking about this.
我们应该专注于主题 A，但现在我们正在谈论这个。
And well it's a problem.
而且这是一个问题。
OK so the moderator is responsible for making sure that doesn't happen.
好的，版主有责任确保不会发生这种情况。
Also making sure people are not fighting or disagreeing.
还要确保人们没有争吵或不同意。
Also making sure that maybe the meeting finishes on time making sure maybe the ideas are on the whiteboard.
还要确保会议按时结束，确保想法可能在白板上。
If there is a whiteboard or on the blackboard if there's a blackboard.
如果有白板或在黑板上如果有黑板。
But I haven't ever seen a meeting on a blackboard before.
但我以前从未见过黑板上的会议。
But anyway they're responsible for orchestrating.
但无论如何，他们负责编排。
We could say the whole thing.
我们可以说整个事情。
And I want to talk about a few phrases we can use a few things we can say to keep things focused.
我想谈谈一些短语，我们可以使用一些我们可以说的东西来保持专注。
So what I want to do is just share with you a few things that the moderator might say to make sure that
所以我想做的只是和你分享一些主持人可能会说的事情，以确保
the meeting doesn't get off track doesn't stray from the purpose.
会议不偏离轨道不偏离目的。
Here's an example Larry has given his proposal about the monthly dinner and let's say Nathan disagrees.
下面是一个例子，Larry 给出了他关于每月晚餐的建议，假设 Nathan 不同意。
He thinks it costs too much money.
他认为这太花钱了。
Then Lisa here's Nathan's idea that it cost too much money and then she starts talking about the budget.
然后 Lisa 这是 Nathan 的想法，认为它花费了太多钱，然后她开始谈论预算。
And she says yeah actually I'm thinking maybe we should increase the budget for events because if we
她说是的，实际上我在想也许我们应该增加活动的预算，因为如果我们
had a bigger budget than we could afford.
预算超出了我们的承受能力。
Blah blah blah.
等等等等等等。
OK so now things are getting off track right.
好的，所以现在事情正在偏离轨道。
This is not good.
情况不妙。
We're not talking about proposals for resolving the issues that we have with morale.
我们不是在谈论解决士气问题的建议。
That's what we're trying to talk about here.
这就是我们要在这里讨论的内容。
So the moderator Linda whoever says good point.
所以主持人琳达谁说的好。
But let's stick to the plan for today's meeting.
但是，让我们坚持今天会议的计划。
So it's a good way to make her feel.
所以这是让她有感觉的好方法。
Hey your ideas not bad.
嘿，你的想法不错。
What you're saying is not crazy.
你说的并不疯狂。
That's fine.
没关系。
Let's stick to the plan for today's meeting.
让我们坚持今天会议的计划。
And you're bringing her back.
而你要把她带回来。
It's a way to say hey hey come back.
这是一种说嘿嘿回来的方式。
Remember we're talking about something else but it's not insulting you're not hurting her feelings by
请记住，我们在谈论其他事情，但这不是侮辱，您不会伤害她的感情
saying it that way.
这么说。
We were about to go off on a tangent about the budget.
我们正要偏离预算。
Maybe we were about to go off on a tangent off track.
也许我们正要偏离正轨。
But thank goodness our moderator is able to deal with that.
但谢天谢地，我们的版主能够处理这个问题。
Good point.
好点子。
But let's stick to the plan for today's meeting.
但是，让我们坚持今天会议的计划。
We need to stay focused or we won't get out of here by 6:00.
我们需要保持专注，否则我们不会在 6:00 之前离开这里。
OK.
好的。
Now the moderator is from mining everybody.
现在版主是来自挖矿大家。
The reason to stay focused and everybody is suddenly realizing Oh right.
保持专注的原因，每个人都突然意识到哦，对了。
If we don't stay focused then we'll have to be here until we resolve this issue and we might have to
如果我们不保持专注，那么我们将不得不待在这里，直到我们解决这个问题，我们可能不得不
work overtime and maybe I want to go home on time today.
加班，也许我今天想准时回家。
So the moderator is also providing everybody at the meeting with a little bit of a motivation sort of
所以版主也提供参加会议的每个人都有一点动力
like a treat we could call it maybe a carrot as something to push them to drive them to stay focused
就像一种款待，我们可以称之为胡萝卜，作为一种推动他们保持专注的东西
and stay on track.
并保持在轨道上。
It's actually a really good way to manage the situation.
这实际上是一个非常好的管理情况的方法。
Another way to express this I think we're getting a little off track now this is like saying a bit.
表达这一点的另一种方式我认为我们现在有点偏离轨道，这就像说一点。
Remember we use a bit to soften things.
请记住，我们使用一点来软化事物。
I think we're getting a little off track.
我认为我们有点偏离了轨道。
Let's not focus on the budget.
让我们不要关注预算。
We're supposed to be talking about ways to promote the company culture.
我们应该谈论促进公司文化的方法。
Let's focus.
让我们集中注意力。
So this is pretty much the same right.
所以这几乎是一样的权利。
Same basic function the same basic idea almost the same phrasing says a slightly different way of saying
相同的基本功能 相同的基本思想 几乎相同的措辞 表达方式略有不同
this a little makes it gentler.
这一点使它更温和。
OK.
好的。
But we're still stating the reality very clearly.
但我们仍然非常清楚地陈述现实。
We're supposed to be talking about ways to promote the company culture.
我们应该谈论促进公司文化的方法。
Let's focus now.
现在让我们集中注意力。
This is balanced between tough and gentle.
这在强硬和温和之间取得了平衡。
The words are gentle.
言语很温柔。
The meaning is tough.
意思是硬的。
If you say to everybody hey stop talking about the budget what's wrong with you people.
如果你对所有人说，嘿，别再谈论预算了，你们这些人怎么了。
You call them.
你打电话给他们。
I don't know stupid or you say things very directly sometimes.
我不知道愚蠢或者你有时说得很直接。
Some people like to communicate that way whatever but sometimes that can make you come across as maybe
有些人喜欢这样交流，但有时这会让你觉得你可能
too strict.
太严格。
And it can make other people shut down.
它可以让其他人关闭。
They don't want to share their opinions anymore because they don't want to get yelled at.
他们不想再分享他们的意见，因为他们不想被骂。
So they'll just be quiet by saying things in a soft way but with a tough and direct meaning we're able
所以他们会保持安静，用温和的方式说话，但我们可以用强硬和直接的意思
to make sure that everybody is on track and people are contributing because they feel like they're also
确保每个人都走上正轨并且人们都在做出贡献，因为他们觉得自己也在
respected.
尊重。
So this is another good one but it is pretty much the same as the previous one.
所以这是另一个很好的，但它与前一个几乎相同。
Finally if we are the moderator of the meeting and we're trying to get things back on track we might
最后，如果我们是会议的主持人，并且我们正在努力让事情回到正轨，我们可能会
say I think it's a good point.
说我认为这是一个很好的观点。
So Linda says something about the budget.
所以琳达谈到了预算。
We should increase the budget.
我们应该增加预算。
We need more money for events.
我们需要更多的钱来举办活动。
I think it's a good point.
我认为这是一个很好的观点。
So we've recognized her and her idea.
所以我们已经认可了她和她的想法。
We haven't shut her down stop talking about that.
我们还没有阻止她停止谈论这个。
Maybe we'll shut her down.
也许我们会关闭她。
That's a good point.
那是个很好的观点。
Makes her feel maybe good about herself right.
让她对自己感觉良好。
So that's great.
那太好了。
But again it's off topic.
但这又是题外话了。
So after we've given someone a compliment.
所以在我们给了某人一个赞美之后。
We then need to say something a little more directly to help people focus.
然后我们需要说一些更直接的东西来帮助人们集中注意力。
This is often how we give feedback as well.
这通常也是我们提供反馈的方式。
When you want to give someone feedback one method is called the sandwich method that has other names
当您想给某人反馈时，一种方法称为三明治方法，它有其他名称
too I like the sandwich method because it's very visual.
我也喜欢三明治方法，因为它非常直观。
Say something positive and encouraging.
说一些积极和鼓舞人心的话。
Then you say the meat of the idea really what you're trying to communicate and then maybe another bun
然后你说这个想法的实质是你想要传达的内容，然后可能是另一个小圆面包
of the burger or a sandwich which is another gentle and soft thing but really it's the meat that you
汉堡或三明治，这是另一种温和柔软的东西，但实际上是你喜欢的肉
want to communicate.
想交流。
So I think it's a good point but it doesn't quite fit with our plan for today.
所以我认为这是一个很好的观点，但它并不完全符合我们今天的计划。
Why don't we deal with that in the next meeting.
我们为什么不在下次会议上处理这个问题。
So that's the bottom of the sandwich.
这就是三明治的底部。
The bottom of the sandwich is hey your idea is a wonderful thing to talk about.
三明治的底部是嘿，你的想法是一个很棒的话题。
But if we talk about it in the next meeting then we're still able to stay on track for today.
但是如果我们在下次会议上讨论它，那么我们仍然可以继续你今天的轨道上。
Then we can deal with today's issue and the budget issue.
然后我们可以处理今天的问题和预算问题。
Maybe tomorrow it's a win win.
也许明天是双赢。
So the first part the top of the sandwich is this the real meat of it is this doesn't quite fit with
所以三明治顶部的第一部分是它真正的肉，这不太适合
the plan for today.
今天的计划。
And then the bottom of the sandwich is this and you can do it.
然后三明治的底部就是这个，你可以做到。
If you're moderating a meeting to make people focus on something right.
如果您正在主持会议以使人们专注于正确的事情。
Say something positive and encouraging then the meat.
说一些积极和鼓励的话，然后是肉。
The real thing you want to communicate then the bottom bun of the burger.
您想要交流的真实事物然后是汉堡的底部面包。
Why don't we deal with that in the next meeting.
我们为什么不在下次会议上处理这个问题。
That's how good your idea is.
这就是你的想法有多好。
It's worth talking about later.
值得以后再谈。
OK.
好的。
And I really like to use this when I give people feedback.
当我向人们提供反馈时，我真的很喜欢使用它。
I like to give direct and honest feedback sometimes very critical.
我喜欢给出直接和诚实的反馈，有时非常关键。
But if I say it's terrible directly they feel hurt.
但如果我直接说这很糟糕，他们会感到受伤。
Maybe they don't want to ask me next time but if I use the sandwich method if I use this structure then
也许他们下次不想问我但是如果我使用三明治方法如果我使用这种结构那么
I can communicate my idea.
我可以交流我的想法。
But at the same time make the other person feel like I respect them enough.
但同时让对方觉得我足够尊重他们。
And of course you've got to try to be honest it may be a good idea.
当然，你必须尽量诚实，这可能是个好主意。
OK.
好的。
So those are some common ways that when you're moderating a meeting you can make sure that things don't
所以这些是一些常见的方法，当你主持会议时，你可以确保事情不会发生
go off track.
偏离轨道。
You can keep things focused and I hope even though we didn't cover every possible thing that can happen
你可以保持专注，我希望即使我们没有涵盖所有可能发生的事情
in a meeting that could be done in a whole course of meetings probably.
在一个可能在整个会议过程中完成的会议中。
I hope that you feel more comfortable with how you can communicate in these specific areas particularly
我希望您对如何在这些特定领域进行交流感到更自在，尤其是
proposals giving feedback on proposals and moderating a meeting and keeping things on track.
提案 对提案提供反馈并主持会议并使事情保持在正轨上。
OK.
好的。
So to practice this what I'd like you to do is come up with another idea for helping boost the morale
所以要练习这个我希望你做的就是想出另一个有助于提高士气的想法
of this company.
这家公司的。
OK imagine you're doing it in a meeting.
好吧，想象一下你在开会。
Do it until you can say your proposal or speak your proposal naturally record yourself.
做到这一点，直到你可以说出你的提议或说出你的提议，自然地记录你自己。
OK if you do it three or four times go back and listen to it and try to make corrections and revisions
好的，如果你做了三四遍，就回去听听，并尝试进行更正和修改
each time then give some critical feedback on the idea.
然后每次都对这个想法给出一些批评性的反馈。
EXPRESS What's wrong with the idea as though you were another person in the meeting.
表达这个想法有什么问题，就好像你是会议中的另一个人一样。
Practice this a few times until you feel comfortable doing both the presentation and the feedback.
练习几次，直到您对演示和反馈都感到满意为止。
Good luck and I will see you in the next lesson.
祝你好运，我们下节课见。